export const personal = [
  {
    question: "WHAT I LIKE IN CODING",
    answer:
      "The first thing i really like in coding is the ability of thinking an idea or a problem and be able to give it physical form and make people use it and interact with it in a beneficial way.I also appreciate the constant learning and growth opportunities that programming offers.As technology advances there is always something new to learn and explore which keeps me engaged and motivated to improve my skills and stay up-to-date with the latest trends and best practices.Also i really like working in a team because we can build something bigger that i could achieve on own and also It allows me to contribute to a project's success while also learning from other team members.",
  },
  {
    question: "IN WHICH FIELDS I AM GOOD AND WHICH NOT",
    answer:
      "I am still in the process of developing my skills and gaining experience in the field. However, I believe that I am very organized and good at problem-solving,I have attention to detail, and I have a GREAT willingness to learn new technologies and evolve my skills through time.In terms of weaknesses I am sometimes impatient when working on a project I really like because I want to watch it finished and see it in action and I get a bit frustrated when things are going slowly or not as well as expected.Also while I appreciate the creativity and flexibility of coding, I sometimes struggle with unstructured or unorganized tasks.This can cause me to feel overwhelmed or uncertain about where to start.",
  },
  {
    question: "How do you handle tight deadlines or high-pressure situations?",
    answer:
      "I prioritize tasks, break them into manageable steps,and i am thinking one thing at a time while ensuring clear communication with my team. If needed, I'm open to putting in extra hours.",
  },
  {
    question: "How do you ensure you continue learning and growing as a developer?",
    answer:
      "Staying updated is crucial in the tech world.So I spend much time every day learning new languages or frameworks by doing personal projects.I also have subscribed to various newsletters to keep me up to date with the latest news.Also i communicate a lot with my colleagues, exchanging opinions about varius subjects.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Describe a time when you had to learn a new technology or language for a project. How did you approach it?",
    answer:
      "For a project, I had to learn ionic with angular. I started with online tutorials, practiced by building an app for students to view my schools current meals, and consulted with colleagues who had experience with this framework",
  },
  {
    question:
      "How do you prioritize tasks when multiple projects are assigned to you simultaneously?",
    answer:
      "I list down all tasks, based on their urgency and importance, and then allocate time blocks for each one.Also I keep clear communication with managers and team members to ensure veryone's expectations are aligned.",
  },
  {
    question: "What's your approach when you're stuck on a coding problem?",
    answer:
      "First, I take a short break to clear my mind. If I'm still stuck, I'll discuss the problem with a colleague or seek solutions online.Also taking a walk and not thinking about the problem is one of the best ways to solve it.",
  },
  {
    question: "How do you handle situations where you have to work with difficult team members?",
    answer:
      "I focus on open communication and try to understand their perspective. It's crucial to remain professional, address any issues directly, and if needed, involve team leads to mediate.",
  },
  {
    question: "How do you approach testing and quality assurance?",
    answer:
      "Testing is crucial to the development process. I start with unit tests to catch early bugs, then move to integration tests. I also believe in the value of end-to-end testing and user acceptance testing to ensure the software meets user expectations. Feedback loops and continuous integration tools help maintain high quality throughout.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "How do you handle a situation where a project is off-track or might miss its deadline?",
    answer:
      "I start by analyzing the root cause of the delay. I then communicate openly with stakeholders about potential risks and work on a revised plan. If possible, I'll prioritize critical features to ensure a partial delivery while seeking ways to optimize the workflow.",
  },
  {
    question: "How do you handle technical debt?",
    answer:
      "I believe in addressing technical debt proactively. Regular code reviews, refactoring, and allocating time in sprints for debt reduction are strategies I employ.",
  },
  {
    question: "What motivates you as a software developer?",
    answer:
      "I'm driven by the joy of solving complex problems and the impact software can have on users and businesses. Continuous learning and the dynamic nature of the tech world keep me engaged and passionate.Also by seeing it as a hobby which I get paid for doing helps a lot :)",
  },
  {
    question: "How do you handle criticism, especially when you believe it may not be justified?",
    answer:
      "I always approach criticism with an open mind. Even if I initially believe it's not justified, I take a moment to reflect on the feedback. Sometimes, it offers a perspective I hadn't considered. If I still have reservations, I'll engage in a constructive conversation with the person to understand their viewpoint better.",
  },
  {
    question: "How do you maintain a work-life balance, especially during tight project deadlines?",
    answer:
      "I prioritize tasks efficiently and ensure that I allocate specific time blocks for breaks and relaxation. During tight deadlines, I might work longer hours, but I always ensure to compensate with some downtime afterward. Clear communication with my team helps in distributing tasks more effectively, ensuring no one is overwhelmed.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What qualities do you believe are essential for effective teamwork, and how do you foster them in a group setting?",
    answer:
      "Effective communication, mutual respect, and trust are vital for teamwork. I always encourage open dialogue in the team, ensure everyone has a voice, and promote a positive, collaborative environment where feedback is appreciated.",
  },
  {
    question: "How do you handle stress or burnout?",
    answer:
      "I've found that regular breaks, physical activity,meditation,mindfulness and hobbies outside of work help manage stress. If I ever feel the onset of burnout, I discuss workload adjustments with my supervisor and ensure I set aside time for self-care.",
  },
  {
    question: "How do you handle conflicts within a team?",
    answer:
      "I believe in addressing conflicts head-on. I usually initiate a conversation with the involved parties to understand their viewpoints and find common ground. Open communication and a solution-focused approach generally help resolve conflicts effectively.",
  },
];
